<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bilal Budhani]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-30T17:16:53+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[BilalBudhani]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bilalbudhani@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 steps to Vim from Sublime Text 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/2013/08/30/3-steps-to-vim-from-sublime-text-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T16:05:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/2013/08/30/3-steps-to-vim-from-sublime-text-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using Sublime Text 2 since quite a while now and really enjoy spending my most of the time playing around code with it. Since I&rsquo;ve a PHP background (where I used to code on Netbeans) I was not motivated to use use on Terminal based editors. However, I gave a try to switch to Vim few months back but the situation was too much demanding at that time. I was learning couple of other new technologies where I didn&rsquo;t wanted them to suffer/compromise and avoided one more constrain on my brain to use Vim. <!-- more --> So, I stood beside Sublime Text 2 and it continued to be my IDE in that struggling period. Until recently, I came across <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/">this great article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/wycats">Yehuda Katz</a> which convinced me to give Vim another good try.</p>

<p>This is the basic setup I did to get started using Vim (on MacOSX)</p>

<h3>Setting up MacVim</h3>

<ul>
<li>Install macvim using homebrew.</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>brew install macvim</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>After installing macvim, I installed <a href="https://github.com/carlhuda/janus">janus-bootstrap</a> which automatically installs and configures required plugins.</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>curl -Lo- https://bit.ly/janus-bootstrap | bash</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>(Optional) Setting up a nice colorscheme is important. You should checkout <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">solarized</a> it has elegant colors which makes me feel nice while working. Fortunately, Janus has solarized built-in I just activated it. (BTW, my iTerm2 also has this same colorscheme)</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>echo 'color solarized'  &gt;&gt; ~/.vimrc.after</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Square has open sourced their in house vim configuration more info <a href="http://corner.squareup.com/2013/08/fly-vim-first-class.html">here</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bingo!</strong> I&rsquo;m done with configuring vim with all the essential plugins out there within 3 steps. But, Not to forget Vim is not done until you know some required shortcuts. I&rsquo;ve compiled the list for my quick reference. Ofcourse, They&rsquo;re available on the internet too.</p>

<h3>List of Not to forget Vim Shortcuts</h3>

<ul>
<li><code>:q!</code> quits the file and discard the changes.</li>
<li><code>:wq</code> saves changes and quits the current file.</li>
<li><code>\n</code> toggles the nerdTree on the left hand side.</li>
<li><code>\ew</code> or <code>:e &lt;filename&gt;</code> opens the file in current buffer.</li>
<li><code>\es</code> or <code>:sp &lt;filename&gt;</code> opens the file in horizontal split pane.</li>
<li><code>\ev</code> or <code>:vsp &lt;filename&gt;</code> opens the file in vertical split pane.</li>
<li><code>\et</code> or <code>:tabe &lt;filename&gt;</code> opens the file in new tab.</li>
<li><code>ctrl/cmd + T</code> opens a fuzzy finder in the root of the project (Sublime Text 2 has this feature too.)</li>
<li><code>gt</code> and <code>gT</code> to change tabs.</li>
<li><code>ctrl+w w</code> will move the cursor in multiple split pane (if there are).</li>
</ul>


<h3>Concluding</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m making myself comfortable in Vim and hopefully this will be a successful attemp. If you&rsquo;re sailing on same ship I would love to hear from you.</p>

<p><em>P.S: I&rsquo;ll keep on updating the Shortcuts as I stumble upon them.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open letter to Mumbai Startups from an Interviewee]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2013/08/19/an-open-letter-to-mumbai-startups-from-an-interviewee/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-19T21:16:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2013/08/19/an-open-letter-to-mumbai-startups-from-an-interviewee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Mumbai Startups,</p>

<p>A few days back I have been interviewed by one of the well known startup based out of Mumbai. The interview was so disgraceful and meaningless, I wasted my 9 hours of time/productivity (Travelling + I was coding for straight 7 hours on the problem which was being emailed to me) and they didn&rsquo;t even borthered to meet me for 15mins in person. Let me describe the scene below a bit, I will try to keep it really short though. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>Background</h3>

<p>One of my friend is working for this startup and so he asked me If I was interested in joining them as well. I was looking for a change so I mailed him couple of my open source projects, personal website and blog link, youtube talk links and link to my LinkedIn profile. He got back to me with an unexpected response stating that company only wants your resume in PDF format. I thought for a while and then I exported my linkedin profile to pdf which quench them.</p>

<p>After that, I was getting pushed by one their employee to come for an interview at the earliest. Since I was stuck with some of my personal commitments and didn&rsquo;t wanted to miss the shot for such a well profiled startup without putting some good amount of efforts to make myself prepared. So, I was not confirming any date with them. Finally, Last week Saturday 11:30 am I got a date from them for the interview.</p>

<h3>The Scene</h3>

<p>When I reached on their specified time I found that I&rsquo;m accompanied by 3 more fellow interviewee bagging their heads with paper and pen on some geometric problem. I got certain that I&rsquo;ll be in the same situation soon. Nevertheless, I was expecting some initial introduction and greetings but without even uttering a single word one their employee (who was immediately assigned to me for an interview) handed over me a pen and paper. He then drew a diagram (I googled it and found that diagram was wrong) and told me to divide it into 4 equal parts(Dude! Seriously?). However, I gave it a try but all my attempts were rejected one by one. Finally, That guy showed me how solve the problem (He took 3-4 attempts himself to get it right).</p>

<p>After this silly task I got to hear some words from them which has &ldquo;Problems have been emailed to me&rdquo;. I was quite happy to know that now I can show off my coding skills and can change their prespective. Stay with me here&hellip; They made me code for straight 6-7 hours approx. mailing one after another problem. As soon as I was solving the problem they were sending newer, lengthier and complex problem without even asking me if I&rsquo;ve any experience in that category. Anyway, I took the challange and gave my 100% to solve those problems and I did well. I was able to hack into the solutions much faster and nicer way (I have the original gist of the problem with revisions). Also, In the middle I was iterating/refactoring my previous tasks&#8217; code as per their inputs.</p>

<p>At this point I was done coding 4-5 hours on their tasks and was not expecting any more task from them. But, my prediction went wrong and I got a new task. This time it was much more lengthier and complex (Basically a Real time rails app). I <a href="https://twitter.com/BilalBudhani/status/360730923270021120">knew</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/supportbee/status/362529988194476032">how to do this task completely</a> and I explained it on a paper too to make my positive impression on them but, They want it to be coded. I then started coding on it and made a real time frontend interface(which took me another hour or so). Backend work was still remaining but I was completely exhausted and was not able to code anymore. So, I called up the guy whom I was assigned and I said &ldquo;I&rsquo;m exhausted and can&rsquo;t code anymore&rdquo; to which he had nothing to respond. I was able to see the sign of negativity on his face. He gave me an expression to just leave but I told him that I&rsquo;m still up tech or personal questions (trying my best to ).</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> They had the courtesy to ask me water and lunch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Young Entrepreneur of the year 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2013/01/13/star-young-entrepreneur-of-the-year-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-13T11:25:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2013/01/13/star-young-entrepreneur-of-the-year-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Expect the unexpected and whenever possible be the unexpected</p></blockquote>

<p>As you might know I&rsquo;m crazy about quotes and I try to&nbsp;correlate my each blog post with them. The above mentioned quote is perfectly fits for this one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At this point, I&rsquo;m very Young Entrepreneur who have just begun my Entrepreneurship journey 3 months back with my idea which I called &lsquo;AdsHub&rsquo; also with a vision to create a dent in the universe, I&rsquo;ll talk about this in detail but in some other blog post. Today, I&rsquo;m writing this post to share my&nbsp;delightful experience of getting awarded as Star Young Entrepreneur of the year 2013 by 6th Indira India Innovation Summit.</p>

<p>A month back from now I received an email from the officials of the event stating</p>

<blockquote>May I request to confirm your presence and graciously agree to accept the award in person at the &ldquo;<b>6th Indira International Innovation Summit 2013</b>&rdquo;.</blockquote>


<p>I couldn&rsquo;t believe at first that this is something happening with me that too at such an early stage. I controlled my excitement from bursting, didn&rsquo;t shared this news with anyone with a hypothesis that it may be false or I interpreted it wrong&nbsp; and wrote an email back confirming. After, receiving a positive reply I jumped out of my seat and shouted in crazy manner to all my&nbsp;colleagues informing them about the award.</p>

<p>Venue was far from my place (Mumbai) i.e Pune, but I was least bothered about the travelling part, Crossing all the hurdles I reached the venue on time. It was a grand event (at least for me) where I was called as &lsquo;Awardee&rsquo; first time in my life. Remarkable hospitality and even more remarkable arrangements. After, giving away awards to 3 categories which was before mine. I was called on the stage with other Entrepreneurs who were awarded in the same category. Being in nervous state (which you can gauge by looking in the video below) but, Somehow I manage to utter some words on the stage, Below is my speech (taken from my Samsung galaxy S2 so excuse the quality)</p>

<h2>Social media updates with photos:</h2>

<p><code>Youtube:</code> <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4MXgJ4c2ees">YouTube link</a></p>

<p><code>Facebook:</code> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/BilalBudhani/posts/512212842143747">Facebook update</a></p>

<p><code>Twitter:</code> <a href="https://twitter.com/BilalBudhani/status/289980671575855106">Twitter update</a></p>

<p>Concluding the post, It was such a powerful capsule for early Entrepreneur like me that amplified my motivations and made my vision more strong. My year started with something very awesome&hellip; I hope this is just the start there are lot more opportunities calling me to tap them and I&rsquo;ll try my level best to do so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My experience with in50hrs pune event]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2012/12/19/my-experience-with-in50hrs-pune-event/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T09:37:59+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.bilalbudhani.me/Entrepreneurship/2012/12/19/my-experience-with-in50hrs-pune-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier last week I was checking out <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> (as what I follow religiously). I stumbled upon on an article which took my interest <a href="http://www.vijayanand.name/2012/12/india-has-a-drought-not-of-investors-but-customers/">India has a drought &ndash; not of Investors, but Customers</a> it was a great read. As the guy who wrote this was Indian I decided to do some research and get a background who is he and what he do. The result was stunning, He was <a href="https://twitter.com/vijayanands">Vijay Anand</a> a well known Indian Entrepreneur who is behind <a href="http://thestartupcentre.com">The Startup Centre</a> I also came to know that these people have something called <a href="http://www.in50hrs.com/">in50hrs</a>. <!-- more --> Since I came to know about this it created an impression on my mind. Fortunately, in50hrs were conducting an event in Pune that too in couple of days after I came to know about it without giving a second thought I registered for the event.</p>

<p>I was unsure about my idea <a href="http://adshub.net">AdsHub</a> which I planned to work on in the event. However, I somehow convince myself to stick to the plan and so I left from Mumbai for Pune to attend the event with one of my friend who is working on the idea with me.</p>

<p>We reached Pune (10:30am) way before the specified time for the event all thanks to my friend who was in charge for tickets. After, Struggling a lot to kill the time we successfully arrived at the venue.</p>

<h2>Game begins</h2>

<p>There was around 30 people in the auditorium and IdeaSmiths were ready to present their ideas. Almost after 8 ideas we got the chance to present our idea. I could feel the audience interest towards our idea but, my bad presentation skill and nervousness made me think that I missed the opportunity. Hosts of the event then announced that there will be a voting session for the ideas so that everyone gets a team to get started. Each person can vote 3 ideas including their own idea. Me and my friend voted for our idea and 2 other ideas which we felt were good. I was stunned to know we got the 2nd highest voting, <strong>iWish</strong> by two microsoft employees was leading. We both were&nbsp;surprised and excited at the same time after knowing the results.</p>

<p>Controlling our excitement and answering almost everyone&rsquo;s questions which were raised after the presentation. We started our work for the demo which was scheduled after 50 hours. Our goal for the event was to brainstorm ourself by figuring out how we gonna take this idea forward, what are the limitations and more importantly walk out with a clear vision about the idea. There were mentors available at the event to help you plan and build an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">MVP</a>, These people were extremely friendly, knowledgable, helpful, experienced etc. etc. <em>(limiting myself I hope you got their phenomena)</em>. Each of them took us one step forward towards our goal mentally and made us believe in ourself <em>(and of course in idea too)</em>.</p>

<p>Every iteration on the idea was empowering our vision and <a href="https://twitter.com/BilalBudhani/status/279902765709398016">kept us engaged</a>. Also, we were surrounded by interesting people whom I highly appreciate for listening to my point of view in healthy debets, helping me to draft an about us page and putting efforts to make us believe that Microsoft is a good company :P.</p>

<p>After all the efforts, fun and <a href="https://twitter.com/prats3112/status/280102907511185408">sleepless nights</a> it was time for the <a href="https://twitter.com/_Tripad/status/280288068081184769">demo</a> with around ~50 audience and <a href="https://twitter.com/santoshdawara/status/280554699411828736">3 judges</a>. We were placed at 6th. Somehow managing my nervousness I went on the stage and started <a href="https://twitter.com/prats3112/status/280624679612473344">my speech</a>. The response was overwhelming, I could see the curiosity in those eyes which were stuck on me. Demo session was followed by a snacks and networking break, after which we left for our place.</p>

<h2>Concluding</h2>

<p>Overall it was a great unforgettable experience for us. We achieved lot more than what we&rsquo;ve aimed for, also some awesome new friends to take back home. Kudos to <a href="http://www.in50hrs.com">in50hrs team</a> keep rocking :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
